正如我们刚才提到的，惯性测量单元的关键元件是传感器
As we just mentioned, the key elements of an inertial measurement unit are sensors that
测量加速度，磁场和角速度。现在，我们要谈谈
measure acceleration, magnetic field and angular velocity. Now, we’re going to talk about
我们如何测量加速度。
how we measure acceleration.
我在这里面前的是所谓的四旋翼飞行器。这是一个飞行机器人。
What I have in front of me here is what’s called a quadrotor. It is a flying robot.
它有四个螺旋桨。并且，通过控制各个螺旋桨的速度，我
It’s got four propellers. And, by controlling the speed of the individual propellers, I
可以使机器上，下，左，右等。真的非常重要
can make the machine go up, down, left, right and so on. Really critically important to
在空中控制这样的机器是一种了解它的方向的平衡感
control a machine like this in the air is a sense of balance knowing its orientation
在3D空间。因此，它有一个惯性测量单元。所以，在这个大的里面
in 3D space. So, it has an inertial measurement unit on board. So, somewhere inside this large
堆叠的电子产品，有一块看起来像这样的板子。该板包含
stack of electronics, there is a board that looks something like this. This board contains
三个加速度计，可以确定其在太空中的滚转角和俯仰角。它包含
three accelerometers, which allow it to determine its roll and pitch angle in space. It contains
三个陀螺仪，测量其围绕三个正交轴的旋转速度。和，
three gyroscopes which measure its rotational velocity around three orthogonal axis. And,
它包含一个三轴磁力计，因此它可以确定它的方向
it contains a three-axis magnetometer, so it can determine its orientation where it’s
朝向地球的磁场前进。
heading with respect to the Earth’s magnetic field.
现在，这个小板是为这个特殊的四旋翼飞机定制的。商业产品
Now, this little board is customised for this particular quadrotor. A commercial product
执行完全相同功能的是这样的设备。它有一个插入的USB端口
that performs exactly the same function is a device like this. It's got a USB port that plugs
进入计算机，但在内部，它包含三个加速度计，三个陀螺仪，和
in to a computer, but internally, it contains three accelerometers, three gyroscopes, and
三个磁力计。现在，这个相同的功能几乎以非常紧凑的形式存在
three magnetometers. Now, this same functionality exists in very compact form inside almost
所有现代智能手机。而且，这可以实现智能手机指南针的应用
all modern smartphones. And, this enables the smartphone compass application so it can
找到北方，它可以确定滚转角和俯仰角。它有时用于游戏控制等。
find north, it can determine roll and pitch angles. It’s sometimes used for game control and so on.
想象一下，我站在电梯或电梯里，我有一个非常简单的
Imagine now that I’m standing in a lift or an elevator, and I’ve got a very simple
我身体的动力模型。它由坐在弹簧上的大众组成。质量代表
dynamical model for my body. It consists of a mass sitting on a spring. The mass represents
我的身体的质量位于我的中心质量点，它坐在一个弹簧上
the mass of my body situated at a point at my centre mass and it’s sitting on a spring
这代表了我下半身和腿部的柔软。现在，随着电梯的启动
which represents the softness of my lower body and my legs. Now, as the lift starts
向上移动，我们感觉暂时更重，那就是重量压在弹簧上。
to move upwards, we feel momentarily heavier, that is the weight pushes down on the spring.
而且，当电梯停下来时，我们感觉暂时更轻，这是因为
And, as the lift comes to a stop, we feel momentarily lighter and this is because of
惯性效应。这意味着它想要保持其当前的速度。所以，当我们
inertial effect. It means that it wants to maintain its current velocity. So, when we
开始时，它想保持原来的0速度，这就是导致它的原因
start off, it wants to maintain its original 0 velocity and that’s what causes it to
落后于升降机的人。并且，它压缩了弹簧，它使它们成为现实
lag behind the person moving up in a lift. And, that compresses the spring, it make them
感觉更重。
feel heavier.
随着升力减速，重量想要保持在垂直速度
As the lift slows down, the weight wants to keep going at the vertical velocity of the
升力导致弹簧伸展，使我们感觉轻一点。
lift and that causes that spring to extend and causes us to feel a little bit lighter.
这是一个小型的现代惯性测量单元，这种类型非常常用
Here is a small modern inertial measurement unit, the type that’s quite commonly used
在各种机器人系统中。小盒子里面有许多传感器，包括
in a variety of robot systems. Inside the little box are a number of sensors including
加速度计。那么，让我们看看盒子内部，看看加速度计的工作原理。和，
accelerometers. So, let’s look inside the box and see how an accelerometer works. And,
它看起来就像我们之前研究的例子。它包含一个质量和一个弹簧。如
it looks just like the example we studied before. It contains a mass and a spring. As
加速度计的主体向上加速，重量延伸弹簧。和，
the body of the accelerometer accelerates upwards, the weight extends the spring. And,
当加速度计减速时，弹簧将重量向上拉。所以，扩展
as the accelerometer decelerates, the spring pulls the weight upwards. So, the extension
弹簧的角度与加速度计的主体的加速度线性相关。这是
of the spring is linearly related to the acceleration of the body of the accelerometer. This is
所有加速度传感装置的基本原理。
the fundamental principle underpinning all acceleration sensing devices.
让我们看看盒子内部，再一次，我们看到一个弹簧和一个质量。群众经常
Let’s look inside the box and, once again, we see a spring and a mass. The mass is often
被称为证明质量。而且，在这个例子中，它的质量为m和扩展
referred to as the proof mass. And, in this example, it’s got a mass of m and the extension
弹簧的符号用符号x表示。现在，我要标记质心
of the spring is denoted by the symbol x. Now, I’m going to mark the center of mass
证据质量及其相对于地面的位移，我将表示它
of the proof mass and its displacement with respect to the ground, I’m going to denote it
由xm。并且，加速度计的主体的位移，我将表示
by xm. And, the displacement of the body of the accelerometer, I’m going to denote by
符号xb。而且，身体的加速度等于xb双点，我可以
the symbol xb. And, so the acceleration of the body is equal to xb double dot and I can
写一个xm，xb和x之间的关系。作用在检测质量上的弹簧力，
write a relationship between xm, xb and x. The spring force acting on the proof mass,
我将打电话给fs，作用于检验质量的重力是质量乘以
I’m going to call fs, and the gravity force acting on the proof mass is the mass multiplied
通过重力加速度g。我可以写出牛顿第二定律，它涉及加速度
by gravitational acceleration g. I can write Newton’s second law which relates the acceleration
质量对两个力作用在弹簧力向上和重力向下作用。
of the mass to the two forces acting on at the spring force upwards and gravity acting downwards.
而且，对于弹簧，我们知道力与弹簧的伸展成正比，
And, for a spring, we know that the force is proportional to the extension of the spring,
我们可以想象，当x增加时，我正在伸展弹簧，它向上拉
and we can imagine that as x increases, I’m extending the spring and it is pulling upwards
越来越大的力量。现在，我们可以结合这些方程并做一点
with a greater and greater force. Now, we can combine these equations and do a little
重新排列和简化。而现在，我能写出一个表达式
bit of rearrangement and simplification. And now, I’m able to write an expression that
将弹簧x的延伸与主体的加速度a和重力相关联
relates the extension of the spring, x, to the acceleration of the body, a, and the gravitational
加速度，g。值得注意的是，它无法区分它们，这一点非常重要
acceleration, g. It’s really important to note that it cannot tell the difference between
加速身体，a或重力加速度，g，这是我们要做的
acceleration of the body, a, or gravitational acceleration, g, and this is something we’ll
过了一会儿。
return to in just a moment.
每个加速度计都有一个敏感的方向，通常标记在身体上
Every accelerometer has a sensitive direction and, typically, that’s marked on the body
加速度计包的。现在，在这个特定的例子中，加速度计测量
of the accelerometer package. Now, in this particular example, the accelerometer measures
在垂直方向上加速，但它对水平加速度不敏感
acceleration in the vertical direction, but it is insensitive to acceleration in the horizontal
方向或在屏幕外的方向。如果我把加速度计放在某个地方休息
direction or in the direction out of the screen. If I place an accelerometer at rest somewhere
在地球表面，加速度计在垂直方向上记录1g的加速度
on the surface of the Earth, the accelerometer records an acceleration of 1g in the vertical
或向上方向，这有点不直观。如果我放弃一些东西，它就会发生
or upward direction and this is a little bit unintuitive. If I drop something, it’s going
加速度计在垂直方向上测量1g，向下加速
to accelerate in the downward direction that the accelerometer measures 1g in the vertical
或向上的方向。而且，这是爱因斯坦等效原则的结果。
or upward direction. And, this is a consequence of Einstein’s Equivalence Principle.
并且，就加速度计而言，这两个示例完全相同。该
And, these two examples are exactly the same as far as an accelerometer is concerned. The
加速度计坐在地球表面，或者如果它坐在火箭中
accelerometer is sitting on the surface of planet Earth, or if it is sitting in a rocket
正在加速向上1克。在这两种情况下，加速度计都会注册
which is accelerating upwards at 1g. In both these cases, the accelerometer will register
在垂直方向上加速1g。重力加速度各不相同
an acceleration of 1g in the vertical direction. Gravitational acceleration varies across the
地球表面。地球不是一个完美的球体。它略微压扁，所以直径
surface of the Earth. The Earth is not a perfect sphere. It’s slightly squashed, so the diameter
在赤道处大于通过极点测量的直径。因为这，
at the equator is greater than the diameter measured through the poles. Because of this,
站在赤道上的人离地球中心更远。
somebody who is standing at the equator is further away from the center of the Earth.
因此，他们经历了较低的重力加速度。所以，我们可以很清楚地看到
So, therefore, they experience a lower gravitational acceleration. So, we can see quite clearly
在这个图中，赤道带的重力加速度明显较低
in this figure here, the gravitational acceleration in the equatorial band is significantly lower
而不是地球温带和极地地区的重力加速度。
than gravitational acceleration in the temperate and Polar Regions of the Earth.
标准重力值取为每秒9.80665米的平方，但请注意重要值
The standard gravity value is taken as 9.80665 meters per second squared, but note the significant
变化取决于你在哪里。您拥有的低成本加速度计
variation depending on where you are. The low cost accelerometers that you have in your
手机也许在你车内的导航系统中都是基于微电子机械
phone and perhaps in the navigation system in your car are based on micro-electromechanical
系统技术和整个器件都是用硅蚀刻出来的。惯性质量或
system technology and the whole device is etched out of silicon. The inertial mass or
弹性腿支撑着质量块。在水平加速的情况下，
proof mass is supported by flexible spring legs. In the case of horizontal acceleration,
惯性质量将向侧面移动。而且，位置的变化是有能力的
the inertial mass will move sideways. And, the change in position is measured capacititively
在这里使用这些传感器能够测量三个加速度非常有用
using these sensors here. It’s really useful to be able to measure acceleration in three
正交方向与右手坐标的x，y和z轴对齐
orthogonal directions aligned with the x, y and z-axis of a right-handed coordinate
帧。今天，您可以购买三轴加速度计作为单个芯片。它包含三个MEMS加速度计
frame. Today, you can buy tri-axial accelerometers as a single chip. It contains three MEMS accelerometer
传感器，电子设备，模数转换器，滤波器和串行IO功能
sensors, electronics, analog to digital converters, filters and a serial IO capability so that
您可以非常轻松地将其连接到微控制器。
you can very easily connect it to a microcontroller.
你可能没有意识到你脑子里有加速度计。在内耳组件中
You may not be aware that you have accelerometers in your head. In the inner ear assembly in
我们每只耳朵都有一对加速度计。而且，这些基础的物理原理
each of our ears, there are a pair of accelerometers. And, the physical principles underlying these
生物加速度计与我们已经讨论过的相同。
biological accelerometers are just the same as those we’ve already been talking about.
检验质量是一堆碳酸钙晶体，它们被称为耳石，
The proof mass is a bunch of calcium carbonate crystals and they are referred to as otoliths,
这意味着字面上的耳石。它们坐在凝胶状的膜上
which means literally ear stones. They are sitting on a gelatinous membrane which serves
作为春天。并且，嵌入在凝胶状膜中的是一堆毛细胞和它们
as the spring. And, embedded in that gelatinous membrane are a bunch of hair cells and they
测量耳石相对于内耳的位移。我们有两个
measure the displacement of the otoliths with respect to the inner ear. We have two of these
每只耳朵中的加速度计，一个称为utricle，一个称为saccule。
accelerometers in each ear, one is called the utricle and one is called the saccule.
并且，它们几乎是正交的，因此可以感知水平方向的加速度
And, they are oriented almost orthogonally, so one senses the acceleration in the horizontal
方向，并且感知垂直方向上的加速度。
direction, and one senses the acceleration in the vertical direction.
当你改变头部的方向时，来自utricle的加速度信号
As you change the orientation of your head, the acceleration signals from the utricle
并且球囊变化并且允许您的大脑确定关于取向的某事
and the saccule vary and allows your brain to determine something about the orientation
你的头部相对于世界坐标系。
of your head with respect to the world coordinate frame.